<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Lazy-Ass Gourmet | David Souther]]></title>
  <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/categories/lazy-ass-gourmet/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-18T08:43:18-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://DavidSouther.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Souther]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[davidsouther@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salmon Bake]]></title>
    <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/07/salmon-bake"/>
    <updated>2012-07-27T14:00:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/07/salmon-bake</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fresh fish feels fantastically filling. This salmon bake is great year round, but an especially nice light summer dish.</p>

<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>Salmon Fillets</li>
<li>1 Bell Pepper</li>
<li>half-dozen spears asparagus</li>
<li>4 medium red potatoes</li>
<li>Olive Oil</li>
<li>Lemon juice</li>
</ul>


<p>Pre-heat oven to 350.</p>

<p>Cover your baking sheet with aluminum foil (makes cleanup much easier, just throw the foil away). Drizzle light oil over the baking sheet.</p>

<p>Scallop potatoes, slicing them between an eighth and a quarter inch, and place the slices on an oiled baking sheet. Add a light dash salt and splash of lemon juice.</p>

<p>Slice pepper. To slice a bell pepper, cut from the top, near the stem, radially down. Rip out the seeds, throw out the stem, and keep slicing along the length of the bell until you have the thickness you want. Alternate pepper slices and asparagus spears in a layer on top of the potatoes. Add a light dash of salt and splash of lemon juice.</p>

<p>Place salmon fillet skin-down on the veggies, and add a splash of lemon juice.</p>

<p>Bake 15 minutes, or until salmon is nice and white.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spaghetti]]></title>
    <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/07/spaghetti"/>
    <updated>2012-07-25T14:00:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/07/spaghetti</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The quickest Italian dish ever. If you can&rsquo;t cook this, you shouldn&rsquo;t cook. (Actually, you should try it a few more times and figure out how to cook.) If you can&rsquo;t make this tasty, try a couple more times.</p>

<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>Spaghetti noodles</li>
<li>1 lbs ground beef</li>
<li>1 can Classico spaghetti sauce</li>
<li>Salt</li>
<li>Olive Oil</li>
</ul>


<p>You&rsquo;re probably cooking your pasta wrong. Don&rsquo;t add pasta to boiling water. There&rsquo;s a weird reaction the outer pasta has that makes it sticky when you do that (and no, oil doesn&rsquo;t help much). Instead, put your dry pasta in a pan, cover with cold water (maybe a &frac14; inch above the pasta), and then turn on the heat. This lets the pasta get all wet and cooked before it starts to get soggy and clump. Add a dash of oil to keep the water from foaming and boiling over. You know now how to cook awesome pasta, of any kind. The only difference is thicker pastas will take longer.</p>

<p>For the sauce, brown the beef. Put a bit of oil in the pan, let it get nice and hot, add the beef, stir until well cooked. Again, don&rsquo;t fuck around with ground beef. Add the sauce, and let it simmer until hot. Depending on the noodles, it should be just the right temperature when the noodles finish.</p>

<h3>Alternatives</h3>

<ol>
<li><p> Different pastas. There are so many friggin pastas. Use the same cold water on top approach, and they&rsquo;ll come out well every time. Except rice noodles, I still can&rsquo;t figure out how to cook those fuckers.</p></li>
<li><p> Make your own sauce! (Guest post, coming soon!) There are probably as many sauce options than there are noodle options, so this is another great place to play around. Even with just the store-bought sauces, try adding different things to your beef when you fry it. I personally like diced onions, bell peppers, and olives.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chili]]></title>
    <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/07/chili"/>
    <updated>2012-07-23T14:00:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/07/chili</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cold day or hot, nothing quite says tasty like a bowl of home-made chili. Probably the easiest dish to take and make your own, so many easy things go into the flavors of a pot of easy chili, you can&rsquo;t help but not experiment with this recipe!</p>

<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>&frac12; lbs ground beef</li>
<li>1 12oz can salsa (your choice, determines spicy level)</li>
<li>1 8oz can refried beans</li>
<li>1 12oz bottle beer (your choice, determines secondary flavors)</li>
<li>Olive Oil</li>
</ul>


<p>This recipe goes easy by trusting the brewer and salsa-er (one who makes salsa?) for the flavors in the chili. With that in mind, choose your favorite salsa and a beer you think would go with that salsa, and start your burners!</p>

<p>Brown the beef. Put a bit of oil in the pan, let it get nice and hot, add the beef, stir until well cooked. Seriously, don&rsquo;t fuck around with ground beef, cook it all the way through.</p>

<p>Add salsa the refried beans. Stir, let beans melt.</p>

<p>Add beer, more beer for thinner, less for thicker. Let simmer, while drinking second beer. Stir occasionally. Simmer at least 10 minutes, longer for more flavor but less stock.</p>

<p>Wipe off counter, serve with beer! You&rsquo;ll be delighted how well the</p>

<h3>Alternatives:</h3>

<ol>
<li><p> Cube cheddar and mozzarella cheese, and replace for beer. Stir <em>constantly</em>, but only until heated. Serve with chips (and beer). Cubing the cheeses into &frac14; inch chunks is important, otherwise they melt weird and you get a really odd texture. Don&rsquo;t use shredded cheese.</p></li>
<li><p> Different salsas, different beers. For the true chef, cook your own salsa and brew your own beer. Brewing is not Lazy-Ass Gourmet, and I don&rsquo;t brew myself, but it is a noble hobby.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lazy-Ass Gourmet]]></title>
    <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/07/lazy-ass-gourmet"/>
    <updated>2012-07-21T14:00:51-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/07/lazy-ass-gourmet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The art of cooking Fast, Cheap, Clean</h2>

<p>Why aren&rsquo;t you cooking for yourself? Do you think it&rsquo;s too expensive? Do you think you don&rsquo;t know how to cook? Or do you just think you don&rsquo;t have enough time in the day? If any of those are your excuse, you&rsquo;re about to lose them. Cooking great food isn&rsquo;t that difficult once you have a few basic dishes, and with the right recipes, you can be cooking great dinners for yourself or your family in half an hour. This is lazy-ass gourmet, and we&rsquo;re going to cook the most fantastic meals in no time at all.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&rsquo;m a busy guy, but man, I love to cook. I&rsquo;ve yet to find a restaurant that can consistently satisfy me with their cooking more than I can do on my own. My secret is finding recipes, and ways to cook those recipes, that take as long to cook as it takes me to watch an episode of the Daily Show (then I watch Colbert while I eat!). Here at lazy-ass gourmet, I&rsquo;ll share a bunch of these recipes, and ways to cook them so that we have a wide combination of things to do with our dishes that we&rsquo;ll always have great food at home, and never get bored with what we&rsquo;re eating.</p>

<p>This isn&rsquo;t <a href="http://www.brokeassgourmet.com">Broke-ass Gourmet</a> (I absolutely recommend her recipes, they are fantastic), but you&rsquo;ll find that while the ingredients for a meal are about the same as a plate would be if you went out, you&rsquo;ll several plates worth, and it will definitely come out much cheaper in the long run. The ingredients I recommend are a step up from college dorm food, but you can have fun shopping around for the best prices on what you find are your favorite things. On the other hand, this isn&rsquo;t Iron Chef. I don&rsquo;t use that many ingredients, I just play with what I have in slightly different ways.</p>

<p>There are a lot of techniques in cooking. It takes some time to get comfortable with a knife. There are a lot of spices and flavors to discover and find out how they work together. These all take your time and experimentation, and frankly half the fun of cooking is trying new things, especially when they go wrong! These are things you really can&rsquo;t learn in a book (though you can make good headway), but just have to try on your own.</p>

<p>There is one thing, however, that I can tell you in the spirit of Lazy-Ass Gourmet. Clean up immediately. As in, before you go on to the next step, wipe off your utensils you just used and the surface you just used. It takes 10 seconds, but saves so much time from the daunting task of cleaning everything at once after you&rsquo;ve cooked. Also, do things that make it easier to keep clean. When you&rsquo;re chopping and peeling onions, keep the trash can right there for the peelings. When you&rsquo;re working at the stove, put a splash guard over your pan and a lid on your pots. These little things make it a hundred times easier to keep your kitchen clean, and yourself happy and lazy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steak & Potatoes]]></title>
    <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/07/steak-potatoes"/>
    <updated>2012-07-21T14:00:14-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/07/steak-potatoes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nothing says good eating like a steaming plate of steaks, mashed potatoes, and country veggies. The best part? It&rsquo;s one of the easiest things you can cook. Follow along, and in half an hour you&rsquo;ll be having better steaks than they server at Morton&rsquo;s.</p>

<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>2 to 4 Fillets, 1-2" thick.</li>
<li>1 can whole kernel corn</li>
<li>1 can sliced carrots</li>
<li>1 can french-cut green beans</li>
<li>1 white onion</li>
<li>4-6 red potatoes</li>
<li>2 tblsp butter</li>
<li>&frac14; quart half-and-half</li>
<li>Salt</li>
<li>Lawry&rsquo;s</li>
<li>Olive oil</li>
</ul>


<p>Quarter the potatoes. We&rsquo;re doing mashed potatoes, so go fast and dirty here. Find the longest, thinnest part of the potato, cut in half, find the next thinnest side, cut in half, then cut the last side two or three times. At this point you&rsquo;ll have &lt;1" cubes of potato. Put those potatoes &amp; some salt in pot. Add water to ~1" above the potatoes. Add a dash (~1 teaspoon) of oil (this stops the water from boiling over. Place the pot over high heat.</p>

<p>Chop the onion. Start by cutting off the ends. I like larger chunks of onion, so I usually slice once through the thickest part of the onion, once through each half, then slice one of the quarters the long way and the other quarter radially. That gives a good combination of fat slices and long slices. Pour a couple dashes of oil into pan (not too much, just enough to start searing the onion). Bring oil to temperature. Over high heat this should take less than a minute; you&rsquo;ll know its ready when the oil starts to have rivulets when it flows over itself. Add the onions, stirring regularly until the onions are lightly cooked. Add some Lawry&rsquo;s. Clear out an area of the pan moving the onions to the side. Add steaks in the clearing, let them cook for about a minute, dash the uncooked side  with Lawry&rsquo;s, turn them over. Drain veggies from the can. Add veggies to the pan, add Lawry&rsquo;s to taste, stir, and cover. Wait about 15 minutes, stirring occasionally.</p>

<p>When potatoes are done (easily pierced by fork), drain in colander and put back in pot. Rinse colander and place on drying rack. Add butter, half-and- half, and salt to potatoes. Mash. This makes the consistency I like; for thicker use more potatoes or less half-and-half; for thinner use less potatoes or thinner milk (whole, skim).</p>

<p>Steaks will take about 5 minutes / level: 5 minutes rare, 10 minutes medium rare, 15 minutes medium well, 20 minutes well done. Test by cutting open; after a few times, you&rsquo;ll get a feel for your stove and know when they&rsquo;re done without needing to check.</p>

<p>Wipe off counter, serve, &amp; enjoy!</p>

<h3>Alternatives:</h3>

<ol>
<li> Add clove, then onion.</li>
<li> Use fresh veggies (adds ~5 minutes to dice).</li>
<li> Use different meat: different steak cuts, pork, chicken, etc.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
