<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Humor | David Souther]]></title>
  <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/categories/humor/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-05T12:45:58-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://DavidSouther.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Souther]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[davidsouther@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[*boink*]]></title>
    <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/04/boink"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T10:44:41-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/04/boink</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://davidsouther.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/funny-animal-gifs-animal-gifs-boink.gif"><img src="http://davidsouther.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/funny-animal-gifs-animal-gifs-boink.gif" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://icanhascheezburger.com/2012/04/12/funny-animal-gifs-boink/">via</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[That Is All]]></title>
    <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/04/335"/>
    <updated>2012-04-09T22:12:24-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/04/335</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://davidsouther.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/1241100353_anchorman-kicking-the-dog.gif"><img src="http://davidsouther.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/1241100353_anchorman-kicking-the-dog.gif" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[So Close!]]></title>
    <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/03/so-close"/>
    <updated>2012-03-19T14:08:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://DavidSouther.github.io/2012/03/so-close</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.minus.com/ibwsWyQ4cuk0rf.gif" alt="So close!" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leap!]]></title>
    <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/2011/12/leap"/>
    <updated>2011-12-20T14:57:11-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://DavidSouther.github.io/2011/12/leap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://icanhascheezburger.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/gif.gif" alt="" /></p>

<p>This is what I think of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S%C3%B8ren_Kierkegaard">Kierkegaard&rsquo;s</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leap_of_faith">Leap of Faith</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interview With a Conspiracy Theorist]]></title>
    <link href="http://DavidSouther.github.io/2011/08/interview_with_a_conspiracy_theorist"/>
    <updated>2011-08-31T23:27:41-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://DavidSouther.github.io/2011/08/interview_with_a_conspiracy_theorist</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What follows is a conversation I had with a conspiracy theorist on Facebook today.</p>

<p><strong>Jen Gross</strong>
seriously.
<a href="http://act.credoaction.com"> Tell Eric Cantor: Release the hostages and stop blocking funds for urgently needed disaster relief</a>
It&rsquo;s outrageous to take advantage of the urgent needs of hurricane survivors in order to cut Medicare, Medicaid &amp; Social Security. But that&rsquo;s what Eric Cantor is doing by refusing to allocate money to disaster relief unless Congress first offsets that money with cuts to vital government programs.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> Why do we only worry about these little issues ?</p>

<p><strong>Jen Gross</strong> because lots of people are flooded out of their homes and dealing w/ some pretty heavy damage. meanwhile eric cantor is putting up red tape, preventing the federal government from taking decisive action to help real people.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> My point is that this happens everyday in third world countries ! Poverty , war , disease and we do nothing ! We are taxed to death illegally and all that money goes to shit ! We could change this world so this stuff doesn&rsquo;t happen ! We must first change the system !</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><strong>David Souther</strong> And how, exactly, do you propose to do that, @Josh Carey?</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> Very simple !Stop supporting the failed system, stop giving them power ! A revolution if u will , they happen all the time throughout history to better the people :)</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> That doesn&rsquo;t sound simple at all. First, what are the broken systems? Second, how are they broken? How does the current popular movements in the Arab Spring effect your rabblerousing revolutionarianism?</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> ‎@ David ! I&rsquo;m at work , let me get home and I will elaborate!</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Sure, I look forward to reading what you have.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> ‎@ David, I&rsquo;ll give u 2 examples of this broken system as u call it . First lets start with the IRS. The IRS has been an illegal system since its unlawful inception in the early 1900&rsquo;s. It is nothing more than a criminal organization. If you do not know this story, you should. Second how about the Federal Reserve. In 1913 the Federal Reserve Act was fraudulently pushed through Congress. In the united States we have, in effect, two governments&hellip;.We have the duly constituted Government&hellip;.Then we have an independent, uncontrolled and uncoordinated government in the Federal Reserve System, operating the money powers which are reserved to Congress by the Constitution. Unelected people run this planet, the government is a front for the Inertnational Bankers ! The world is not as it seems, it is how it is presented to us . As for the uprising in the arab world ! I&rsquo;m not sure, I don&rsquo;t care to comment .</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Last I checked, the IRS was started with the position of the Commissioner of Internal Revenue under Lincoln in 1862. That agency was renamed in the 1950s as the Internal Revenue Service. The commissioner and chief counsel are appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate. The event I think you&rsquo;re referring to in the &ldquo;early 1900s&rdquo; would be the 16th amendment to the constitution in 1916 authorizing an income tax. Now, I&rsquo;m not a JD, but I do believe that there is no higher law in this nation than the constitution. Actually, I don&rsquo;t need to be a JD for that- the document spends most of Article 6 saying just that.</p>

<p>The Federal Reserve was founded in 1913, and does not, in fact, have oversight by the executive branch. However, the Fed is directly responsibly to congress, and thus does have indirect oversight by the people. I will use my &ldquo;I am not a JD&rdquo; line again and say, while not studied in this area of constitutional law, it seems the first 3 enumerated powers of congress in Article 1 Section 8 speak precisely to this issue of finding some mechanism to regulate the monetary proceedings of this nation. Whether the fed is the best such mechanism would, I think, be a good debate, but calling its passage fraudulent, while then stating it is anti-constitutional, seems a bit of a stretch.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> Not only is there no law that requires most Americans to file an individual tax return, but the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) wasn&rsquo;t even created by an act of Congress! As for the federal Reserve, Woodrow Wilson put it best ! &ldquo;I am a most unhappy man. I have unwittingly ruined my country. A great industrial nation is controlled by its system of credit. Our system of credit is concentrated. The growth of the nation, therefore, and all our activities are in the hands of a few men. We have come to be one of the worst ruled, one of the most completely controlled and dominated Governments in the civilized world &mdash; no longer a Government by free opinion, no longer a Government by conviction and the vote of the majority, but a Government by the opinion and duress of a small group of dominant men. &rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Credit is an interesting beast, but by no means illegal. I&rsquo;m going to need more than the words of a cranky old President to convince me the entire system is illegal.</p>

<p>As for the founding of the IRS:
The Revenue Act of 1862
Internal Revenue Service Restructuring and Reform Act of 1998</p>

<p>Still not a lawyer, but <a href="http://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/html/uscode26/usc_sec_26_00006012----000-.html">25 U.S.C. § 6012</a> Persons required to make returns of income looks like a few laws requiring most Americans to file tax returns.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> The IRS is not a U.S. Government Agency. It is an Agency of the IMF. The IMF is an Agency of the UN.</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> ‎&hellip;&hellip;&hellip;&hellip;..</p>

<p>What the FUCK!? Ok, I was playing along, but now you&rsquo;re just going batshit crazy. Or trolling. Please, tell me you&rsquo;re trolling, and not serious?</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> I&rsquo;m serious ! google it !</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> No. I will let you post links to that particular ball of mental fuck-upedness.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> It&rsquo;s not some giant seceret , Ron Paul talks about it !</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> <a href="http://truth11.com/2011/02/02/thirty-little-known-facts-about-america/">http://truth11.com/2011/02/02/thirty-little-known-facts-about-america/</a></p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> I&hellip; buh&hellip; I don&rsquo;t even know what to say to that crockery&hellip;
Ok, I&rsquo;ll choose a couple of the easier ones, and then let you move back in with&hellip; whatever it is you keep yourself crazy with. (If there were a God, he would reveal himself in this moment by having you tell me you&rsquo;re just joking with all this. On the other hand, at least I&rsquo;m getting good reading out of it. The laws, not you or your fellow&hellip; whatever the hells you are.)</p>

<p>&ldquo;5. The U.S. does not have any employees because there is no longer a United States. No more reorganizations. After 200 years of bankruptcy it is finally over. <a href="http://waterindustry.org/12803.htm">Executive Order 12803</a>&rdquo;</p>

<p>Section 1. Definitions. For purposes of this order: (a) Privatization means the disposition or transfer of an infrastructure asset, such as by sale or by long-term lease, from a State or local government to a private party.</p>

<p>‎"Sec. 3. Privatization initiative. To the extent permitted by law, the head of each executive department and agency shall undertake the following actions: (a) Review those procedures affecting the management and disposition of federally financed infrastructure"</p>

<p>Etc. Generally, this XO calls for privatizing <em>SOME</em> infrastructure (roads, bridges, trains, electrical lines, etc). Hardly, &ldquo;No longer a united states&rdquo;</p>

<p>‎"1. The IRS is NOT a U.S. Government Agency. It is an Agency of the IMF."</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t find CV-93-405E-EJE U.S.D.C.I.</p>

<p>Public Law 94-564 provides a mechanism for Bretton Woods system, an international monetary treaty, but no indication of handing the IRS over to the IMF.</p>

<p>Public Law 102-391 is an appropriations law for foreign financing. There is a large section stating that the US shall have a representative at the IMF. It does not mean the IRS is an agent of the IMF.</p>

<p>Fuck it, I&rsquo;m done. Go&hellip; go be crazy. I&rsquo;m done.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> International Bankers founded the UN! The same that privately own the Federal reserve! They own all the centeral banks of the countries of this world with the exception of a few !</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> This is why we get no where in this world :( just blow it off!</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Yes, and 9/11 was a missile planted by Cheney, the moon landing happened in a roswell sound stage, the middle ages never actually happened, and you forgot, those UN bankers are actually dinosaurs.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> Well I thought we were having a mature conversation, obviously not.</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> No, we stopped having a mature conversation when you spouted the IRS is part of the IMF conspiracy.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> it&rsquo;s not a conspiracy lol</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Yes, and Rick Santorum is not a bigot.</p>

<p>‎"A conspiracy theory is a belief which explains an event as the result of a secret plot by exceptionally powerful and cunning conspirators to achieve a malevolent end.&ldquo; How is what you&rsquo;ve been presenting not a conspiracy theory?</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> This world is run in secret by shadow governments! You might want to look into &ldquo;human farming&rdquo; . Maybe this may help u understand the world better !</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thelawthatneverwas.com/">http://www.thelawthatneverwas.com/</a></p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Fuck it, sure, here&rsquo;s another link.
<a href="http://docs.law.gwu.edu/facweb/jsiegel/Personal/taxes/IRSrefuses.htm#show">http://docs.law.gwu.edu/facweb/jsiegel/Personal/taxes/IRSrefuses.htm#show</a></p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> Why are people beating the IRS law then ?</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Citation, please. Also, define &ldquo;beating&rdquo;</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> Have u even looked into the cases? Do you think that &frac34; of the states would say income tax is ok ?</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Please, PLEASE, stop crossing your arguments. It&rsquo;s worse than the Ghostbusters' proton streams.</p>

<p>You link to Bill Benson&rsquo;s site. He links to no corroborating evidence, just &ldquo;Buy my book!&rdquo; A quick google search for &ldquo;Bill Benson&rdquo; has <a href="http://www.quatloos.com/bill_benson_debunked.htm">http://www.quatloos.com/bill_benson_debunked.htm</a> as the second hit. The 3rd link is in support, 4th and 5th in opp, and the 6, about a Canadian hockey player. I can&rsquo;t find links to the actual court case Benson bitches about.</p>

<p>Now, back to two questions ago. What do you mean by &ldquo;Beating&rdquo; the IRS? Neither Benson, nor those using his arguments, seem to be &ldquo;Beating&rdquo; the IRS. They are soundly defeated in court.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> ok! you&rsquo;re offically brainwashed. Popular public opinion does not mean it&rsquo;s a fact . later !\</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Try using the Benson argument in court. See how far you get.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> Try keeping a open mind and see how much u learn better yet !</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Ok, let&rsquo;s back up a ways. At the beginning of this discussion, you state we are &ldquo;taxed to death&rdquo; and complain that we could be doing something to help third-world countries. You imply a revolution of some form is what we need. Let us, for the sake of me &ldquo;keeping an open mind&rdquo; assume, purely for the sake of argument, the IRS is illegal/the IMF/etc. How would you propose such a revolution occur?</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> first we have to sway public opinion I guess ! People dub it &ldquo;awakening &rdquo;.</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Ok. How will you do that? And what would you do then?</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> I think it eventually unfolds, I can&rsquo;t say what will happen! some people think we become more intune with the universe in a holistic sense! Much knownledge the government has hidden from us in order to keep us productive and them in control I believe !</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> So&hellip; you don&rsquo;t actually have anything pragmatically constructive to add to the conversation?</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> A shift is taking place, we&rsquo;re becoming aware ! don&rsquo;t get me started on UFO&rsquo;s</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> No, you&rsquo;re right. Please, don&rsquo;t start on UFOs. You&rsquo;ve shed enough crazy tears for the day.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> thats the problem why more people not speak out ! they ridicule others! I don&rsquo;t care anymore becasuse i know as do many other people that this life need to be seen with a open mind ! it&rsquo;s amazing what passes for adulthood in this world !</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> It&rsquo;s also amazing what passes as acceptable typing skills in this world.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> It&rsquo;s not acceptable to question life, this is not in accordance with popular public opinion ! I seek a better world at my very heart, if that&rsquo;s wrong then I don&rsquo;t wanna be right !</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> I believe you seek that better wold in your heart. At your heart would imply a proximity precariously close to the metaphorical world revolving around you. Also, what&rsquo;s with the spaces before the exclamation marks? It adds yet another difficulty to reading what you write.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> Maybe u could stay focused on the issues instead of grammar ?</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Dude, you&rsquo;re long past talking about issues. You have discredited yourself in so many ways, it&rsquo;s kinda&hellip; whatever. Yes, questioning the world is a good thing. That said, presenting answers that are factually wrong has moved long past questioning and into lala land.</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> well I&rsquo;m sorry u feel that way ! so foreign it must be for you. I guess when I was your age I thought much the same way you do.</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> What way do I feel? I&rsquo;ve never been psychoanalyzed over the internet by a conspiracy theorist before!</p>

<p><strong>Josh Carey</strong> lol very cute ! good night !</p>

<p><strong>David Souther</strong> Night. Sweet dreams! I hope the aliens don&rsquo;t anal probe you!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
